

■ s.martin.20@ucl.ac.uk | ★ sophmrtn.github.io | • sophmrtn

Research Interests

I am a PhD student on the i4Health CDT at University College London with an interest in healthcare applications of artificial intelligence. My research focus is on explainable methods and interpretable deep learning in medical imaging. I'm also excited by the use of AI for personalised treatment and enjoy discussions about model bias, fairness and ethics.

Education

University College London

PHD IN AI & MEDICAL IMAGING (1+3, ESPRC-FUNDED) 2020 - Present

Imperial College London

London

UPPER SECOND CLASS (HONS) MSCI PHYSICS 2016 - 2020

St Angela's Ursuline School

 A Level: 3A*'s (Maths, Further Maths, Physics) & 1A (History)
 2014 - 2016

 GCSE: 9A*s (inc. Maths and English Language) & 2As + FMSQ
 2009 - 2014

Research Projects

Evaluating Explanation Methods in Deep Learning for Stroke Classification

University College London

MRES RESEARCH PROJECT

Oct 2020 - May 2021

• This project evaluated several state-of-the-art explanation methods to probe a neural network trained to classify stroke patients from healthy controls. It was supervised by Dr James Cole and Professor Frederik Barkhof during the MRes part of my PhD.

A Network Science Perspective on Signal Propagation in the Brain

Imperial College London

MSci Research Project

Oct 2019 - May 2020

• Supervised by Professor Kim Christensen, I developed a cellular graph network to model excitation spread across structures such as small-world, stochastic model and Barabasi-Albert hub network. This made use of graph theory and criticality analysis.

Sensitivity Studies of the 5 MeV Distortion at SoLid Utilising Machine Learning

Imperial College London

BSc Research Project

Oct 2018 - May 2019

• Supervised by Dr Daniel Saunders, this project evaluated the use machine learning to detect a distortion in the anti-electron neutrino energy spectrum. This signal vs. background problem is highly transferable and was a useful application of statistical data analysis.

Industry Experience ____

Illumina Cambridge

BIOINFORMATICIAN Jul 2019 - Oct 2019

- I used Python to build a pipeline that used machine learning to identify tumour-only variants from genetic data.
- Explored feature visualisation/engineering methods and hyperparameter optimisation to improve performance.
- I used the Sun Grid Engine cluster computing framework to submit jobs for batch processing.

Open Energi London

Data Scientist, Internship

Jul 2018 - Sep 2018

- I contributed to a project to improve asset performance for rapid grid frequency response.
- Code was developed in Python, Git was used to collaborate with other developers and SQL was required to interact with the database.
- I was able to highlight opportunities for business development and presented my findings to the company.

Teaching Experience

Introduction to Deep Learning

Department of Computer Science

POSTGRADUATE TEACHING ASSISTANT (PGTA)

Oct 2021 - Jan 2022

• I assisted with teaching and marking during this course and delivered a guest lecture on Model Interpretation.

Awards & Publications

AWARDS

2022	2nd Place, NeuroHACK Hackathon, DEMON Network	Virtual Event
2021	Finalist, 15th Annual London Hopper Colloquium	Virtual Event
2016	Winner, Worshipful Company of Coachmakers and Coach Harness Makers' Jaguar Land Rover Bursary	London

PUBLICATIONS

Conference Paper, Liam F. Chalcroft, Jiongqi Qu, Sophie A. Martin, Iani JMB Gayo, Giulio V. Minore, Imraj

RD Singh, Shaheer U. Saeed, Qianye Yang, Zachary M. C. Baum, Andre Altmann, Yipeng Hu, Development and evaluation of intraoperative ultrasound segmentation with negative image frames and multiple observer labels.

ASMUS, MICCAI

Other Activities

The Blackett Lab Family C.I.C

Project Partners Education

Londor

• I generate social media content, lead website development, and manage communications for the organisation.

- Somerate so statement contents, tead wessite development, and manage

London

Jun 2020 - Present

BOARD TRUSTEE Mar 2020 - Present

• I help facilitate the growth this educational charity by attending meetings and consulting on teaching materials.

Google GetAhead Program

Jul 2021 - Sep 2021

Virtual Event

• I participated in a 6-week virtual program for selected CS students across EMEA. The program involved technical challenges, YouTube live trainings and interview workshops.

Skills

PARTICIPANT

Programming Python, MatLab, Bash, SQL, Git, LaTeX, Cluster Computing

Web HTML5, CSS, Bootstrap 4, Javascript

General UK Driving License, English (Native), French (B1)